# WENDY CHUN

5250 University Drive, 423-D Jenkins, Coral Gables, Florida 33146 • Phone: 305.284.1387 • email: wchun@bus.miami.edu

#### **SUMMARY**

Nationally recognized online strategy and mobile innovation leader with more than 10 years of development and project management experience for a Fortune 500 Company. Successful track record of delivering several multimillion-dollar projects from design, development to deployment. Implemented innovative Internet based technology solutions to several large financial services institutions. Holding numerous technical certifications as well as an MBA degree, published a technical book on Microsoft's C# development language prior to Visual Studios' .NET launch. Served on several industry leading standards organizations and technical advisory committees.

#### **AREAS OF STRENGTH**

Management • Research • Leadership • Analysis • Problem-Solving • Organization

#### **ACCREDITATIONS**

Project Management Professional (PMP) • Certified Scrum Master (CSM) • Microsoft Certified Solution Developer (MCSD) PRINCE2 Agile Practitioner (P2AP) • Team Kanban Practitioner (TKP) • Certified Six Sigma Master Black Belt (CSSMBB)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# UNIVERSITY OF MIAMI, Coral Gables, Florida

2008 - Present

# Lecturer, School of Business Administration (2016 – Present)

Business and Technology Department – BTE 210 Fundamentals of Technology and Innovation • BTE 417 Fundamentals of Technology Project Management • BTE 617 Information Technology Project Management • BTE 646 IT Planning and Project Management; Management Science Department – MAS 663 Project Management and Modeling

### Adjunct Lecturer, School of Business Administration (2015)

Business and Technology Department – BTE 210 Fundamentals of Technology and Innovation • BTE 417 Fundamentals of Technology Project Management • CIS 410 Fundamentals of Information Systems

### Adjunct Graduate School Instructor, School of Business Administration (2015 - 2016)

Marketing Department - Adjunct Graduate School Instructor for Marketing Majors in Adobe Photoshop, Dreamweaver, and InDesign. Course curriculum design, classroom lecture, and e-learning certificate modules via Lynda.

#### Director, Online Communications ~ web and mobile technologies (2008 – 2016)

Position provides strategic coordination, planning and implementation of the University of Miami Alumni Association (UMAA) communication programs, including alumni relations, annual giving, and customer service areas for 165,000 target constituents. Responsibilities include management and content of the Alumni, Alumni Center, Alumni Weekend, Annual Giving, Stories of U websites, program specific micro-sites, management and administration of the Alumni Online Directory and Alumni Volunteer System in coordination with hosting vendor, writing, editing and publishing two electronic newsletters, development and management of social media strategy, provide editorial support for alumni program marketing and promotions and annual giving stewardship communications. Manage the R&D, strategy and future implementation efforts of the UMAA utilization of Web 2.0/3.0 and mobile technologies. Technologies utilized include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Codelgniter, XML, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap, WordPress, Xcode (iOS).

- 2012 Blackboard Catalyst Award for Mobile Innovation Winner
- BlackBoard World 2012 Conference Speaker, Marketing and Branding Our Institutions with Mobile
- 2012 American Marketing Association (AMA) Symposium Speaker, How UM is Using a Mobile App to Control Their Brand
- Chair, University of Miami Web Advisory Committee (Campus Wide) and Digital Communications Advisory Group
- Author, American Marketing Association (AMA) Symposium Paper on UM Mobile Innovations and Branding
- Project Manager, University of Miami Mobile Application Development "UMobile"

### BROWARD COUNTY COMMISSION, Fort Lauderdale, Florida

2004 - 2008

### Information System Analyst IV / IT Manager, Office of Equal Opportunity (2006-2008)

Position provided project management, application development, and management of support services for Equal Opportunity, Small Business, Civil Rights, and Internal Investigations Divisions. Responsibilities included reviewing programming techniques, recommendation of information system solutions, supervision, project management, design, development, testing and deployment. *Projects*: Website for Broward County's Americans with Disabilities Act Compliance, Internal Investigations Audit Applications, County's Equal Employment Opportunity Reporting Services, and Division Development Infrastructure.

#### Senior Information Technology Specialist, Office of Information Technology (2004-2006)

Provided design and development expertise to numerous Broward County wide information technology projects. Responsibilities included requirements gathering, documentation, project management, design, development, testing and deployment. *Projects:* Small Business Division Certification Application (NACO award 2006); Calendar of Events, Emergency Notification, Broward County Public WIFI, Revenue Property Tax Collection, Revenue Occupational License Renewal, Board of Rules and Appeals Online, Broward County Credit Card Processing Component, Wachovia ACH, Building Code Services Credit Card Integration, etc.

# Technical Editor (Freelance)

Review and recommend books relating to programming and Internet technologies. Technical editing books of current and upcoming Microsoft .NET technologies.

### SUNGARD DATA SYSTEMS, Miami, Florida

1999 - 2003

### Assistant Vice President, Research Development (2001-2003)

Evaluated current technology trends to be implemented into future product life cycles. Developed strategic partnerships with leading edge technology vendors to cross promote and implement key products upon launch. Managed next phase product development as well as change management. (Technologies utilized: .NET, ASP.NET, VB.NET, C#, Passport, Visual Studios 6.0, XML, XP Platform).

- Managed the conversion and enhancement of a windows based sales illustration system to a scalable web application. This web
  application was sold to 6 large financial institutions within 2002/2003.
- Managed the R&D effort for the company's first insurance product engine web service with a supporting UI.

### **Assistant Vice President, Internet Development (1999-2000)**

Overall management of Internet projects from initial business requirements through specifications, design, development, deployment and maintenance. Duties also included management of client relations/expectations and liaison to hosting operational staff.

Deployed first Sales Illustration Web Application in the industry. (ASP; JavaScript; XML; COM; VC++; VB; ADO, OLE DB; MS SQL; SSL)

SAM'S PUBLISHING 2002

### Author - Teach Yourself C# in 24 hours (Freelance)

Co-authored introductory book on Microsoft .NET C# Language prior to RTM. Topics of discussion included the Visual Studios .NET environment, basic UI, programming constructs, data manipulation, and best practices.

#### FINANCIAL DATA PLANNING, Miami, Florida

1992 - 1999

#### Assistant Vice President, Special Projects (1998 – 1999)

Responsibilities included evangelism of modern technologies and advanced products to target sectors. Managed projects from the initial proposal stage through design, development, and deployment. Technologies utilized: COM; VB5; ADO, Access; MS SQL.

 Key player in selling and managing a \$2.5 million dollar contract for an integrated CRM/Financial Planning package to one of the largest South African Insurance companies.

#### Assistant Vice President, Contact Partner (1997 – 1998)

Managed and deployed a CRM for financial services with 40,000+ customer base. Responsibilities included client management and project management. Technologies used: COM; VB3; VB4; DAO; Access.

#### Product Development/Project Manager (1995 – 1997)

Responsibilities included project management, development, deployment, and maintenance of a Contact Management System. Managed programmers, account executives, Home Office clients, technical support staff, and test leads.

### **Developer/Technical Development Manager (1992 – 1995)**

Responsibilities included programming, management of developers, and research & development. Technologies used: VB3; VB4; DAO; Access.

### PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

Project Management Institute (PMI) • American Marketing Association (AMA) • Microsoft .NET Authors; Microsoft Product Advisory Panel • MS SQL Server • Windows Visual Studio .Net Beta Product Groups • ACORD Olife Technical Committee

# TRAINING CERTIFICATES

Gamification, Coursera, Wharton School Certificate, 2013 • Microsoft Project, 1998, 2005

ACORD, XML & ACORD XML Standards, 2000 • Developing Solutions with Commerce Server and BizTalk Server, 2001

Crystal Reports, 1998 • Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc., ESRI – ARC Info, 1992

#### **LANGUAGES**

Fluent in English and Spanish

# **EDUCATION**

Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida B.S., Computer Science, Minor; Mathematics

**University of Miami**, Coral Gables, Florida M.B.A., Specialty: International Business